Contact

4242158919 (Mobile) antonydeepak@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/antonyd (LinkedIn) github.com/antonydeepak (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Microsoft SQL Server C# ASP.NET

Languages

French (Elementary)
English (Full Professional)
Tamil (Professional Working)

Patents

Faster Determination Of A Display Element's Visibility

Antony Deepak Thomas

Software Engineer

Mountain View

Summary

I build back-end infrastructure\libraries\services. Some of my strengths include understanding complexity, providing robust implementation, getting to the bottom of problems, attention to detail and caring about the product. I have good grasp of system fundamentals and have worked in all layers of software stack.

I follow articles and discussions from a hacker news, lobster.rs and reddit programming. I am an avid reader. I maintain my academic bonds through MOOC platforms such as Coursera.

https://github.com/antonydeepak

Experience

Facebook
Software Engineer
June 2021 - Present (1 year)
San Francisco Bay Area

laaS Host Management/Containers//Systemd Infrastructure

Reddit, Inc.
Software Engineer
September 2019 - June 2021 (1 year 10 months)
San Francisco Bay Area

- Core backend engineer on Reddit's live video streaming platform(http://reddit.com/rpan).
- Implemented high-performance Graph abstraction layer on top of Redis storage cluster
- Implemented multi-CDN routing that saved significant \$ in infrastructure cost.
- Implemented near real-time video indexing infrastructure on top of Solr to power ranking and relevance

Microsoft

6 years 1 month

Software Engineer (Artificial Intelligence & Research)
September 2017 - August 2019 (2 years)
Sunnyvale, CA

- Worked in Natural Language Understanding(NLU) library for traversing Bing's Knowledge graph.
- Wrote wrappers for different spellers managed wrappers for native C++ library; network wrapper for Bing Speller library.
- Wrote infrastructure modules for building inverted index using different storage technologies such as Sql Server, Redis and Lucene.
- Refactored core components for Natural Language Understanding(NLU) library defining APIs and interface boundaries.
- Built many extensions to the Natural Language Understanding(NLU) library; particularly in syntax (POS Tagger, Tokenizer, Speller, language models) and semantics (predicate transforms) layer.
- Implemented distributed logging and telemetry stack.
- Devops for build monitoring, deployment and automatic rollback.
- Worked on various performance optimizations index tuning, memory & CPU bottlenecks, network IO bottlenecks
- Wrote web and console test hosts for NLU library.
- Known for writing, and for helping others write, efficient & maintainable code with good design principles.

Stack: C#, PowerShell, JavaScript, Bootstrap CSS, .Net, Asp.Net Core MVC, Azure

Software Engineer (Bing)
December 2015 - August 2017 (1 year 9 months)
Sunnyvale,Ca

- Worked on virtualizing applications that get streamed from cloud to web (https://tinyurl.com/zafgytm).
- Implemented backend APIs for the streaming service.
- Implemented dynamic resolution and screen fitting algorithms for RDP web client.
- Implemented Inter-Process message passing(IPC) between non-privileged processes and privileged agents in the VM.
- Implemented security layers symmetric encryption for token distribution, public-private authentication, VM level security policies and privileged process isolation through impersonation.

- Added secure Websocket layer on top of OSS Websockify (https://tinyurl.com/ybwftasz).
- Other Devops and engineering practices expected from a responsible Software Engineer.

Stack: C#, PowerShell, JavaScript, .Net, Asp.Net Core MVC, RDP, Azure, Microservices

Software Engineer (Bing)
August 2015 - December 2015 (5 months)
Sunnyvale, Ca

- Worked on an experimental effort to index mobile applications in iOS and Android platforms.
- Wrote data scraping modules for iOS using code injection frameworks such as Cydia.
- Wrote data scraping and screen stitching algorithms for Android.
- Wrote log analytics and data mining scripts for Microsoft's big data store for the OneNote search team.

Stack: Objective-C, Java, iOS, Android, Cydia

Software Engineer (Microsoft Advertising) August 2013 - August 2015 (2 years 1 month) Sunnyvale,CA

- Worked on Microsoft Advertising SDK for various platforms.
- Implemented the MRaid 2.0 standard for iOS platform.
- Worked on image carousel and click-to-video ad experience layout for Xbox 360.
- Implemented a custom video ad experience layout for Samsung Galaxy S6 for Xbox One.
- Contributed to the Windows 10 lock screen. Worked on the core logic, unit tests and publisher web portal.

Stack: Objective-C, JavaScript, Lua, C#, Windows UWP

JPMorgan Chase (Consultant)
Software Developer
June 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 3 months)
Greater Chicago Area

• Developed business applications using C#.Net, SQL Server and some Java stack. Worked mostly on code refactoring and feature addition.

Toyota Motor Sales (Consultant) Web Developer October 2008 - May 2011 (2 years 8 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

• Developed web applications using Asp.Net forms with SQL Server as backend. Predominantly used Asp.Net, IIS, and SQL Server(data normalization and query optimization) and other custom frameworks based on client's needs.

Toolkit: C#, VB, SQL Server 2000 & 2005, AspNET v 1.1, ADONET, Aqualogic and SSRS.

Education

Anna University
Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Coursera

Computer Science